<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Property Investment on Bush Digital Guides</title>
    <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/tags/property-investment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Property Investment on Bush Digital Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/tags/property-investment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Property Investment Strategies Australia 2026: How to Add Value and Build Wealth</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/property-investment-strategies-australia-2026/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/property-investment-strategies-australia-2026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Australian property market in 2026 looks fundamentally different from the speculative frenzy of 2021–22. Interest rates have stabilised, affordability pressures remain real, and the easy-money days of bidding on anything with four walls are over.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: disciplined investors who focus on fundamentals are doing extremely well. The 2026 market rewards strategy over speculation — and the biggest opportunities right now are in value-add approaches that create equity rather than just hoping the market lifts your boat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Granny Flat Investment Australia 2026: The State-by-State Guide to Boosting Your Rental Yield</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/granny-flat-investment-australia-2026-state-by-state-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/granny-flat-investment-australia-2026-state-by-state-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been sitting on a decent-sized block wondering how to squeeze more income out of it, you&amp;rsquo;re not alone. Granny flat investment in Australia has absolutely exploded over the past few years — and in 2026, the numbers are making more sense than ever.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With national home values up 8.8% over 2025 according to PropTrack, rental vacancy rates still tight in most capitals, and building costs starting to stabilise after the post-COVID blowout, adding a secondary dwelling to your existing property is one of the smartest value-add plays going around.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zoning Reform Could Slash $100K Off House Prices — What It Means for Property Investors</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/zoning-reform-property-investment-australia-2026/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/zoning-reform-property-investment-australia-2026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What if the biggest opportunity — and the biggest threat — to your property portfolio isn&amp;rsquo;t interest rates, CGT changes, or immigration numbers?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What if it&amp;rsquo;s the way councils draw lines on maps?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Grattan Institute has just dropped a major report arguing that Australia could knock &lt;strong&gt;more than $100,000 off the typical house price&lt;/strong&gt; simply by changing how we zone our suburbs. No new taxes. No government handouts. Just letting people build the homes that are actually needed, where they&amp;rsquo;re actually needed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CGT Discount Changes: What Australian Property Investors Need to Know in 2026</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/cgt-discount-changes-what-property-investors-need-to-know-2026/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 08:30:00 +1030</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/cgt-discount-changes-what-property-investors-need-to-know-2026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been anywhere near the news this past fortnight, you&amp;rsquo;ll have noticed something big brewing: the federal government is openly floating changes to the capital gains tax discount. For the first time in years, senior Labor figures aren&amp;rsquo;t shutting down the conversation — they&amp;rsquo;re leaning into it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For property investors, particularly those of us running value-add strategies, this could be a genuine game-changer. So let&amp;rsquo;s cut through the political noise and figure out what&amp;rsquo;s actually happening, what it means for your portfolio, and whether you should be panicking or planning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NDIS SDA Housing Investment in 2026: The Oversupply Nobody Warned You About</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/ndis-sda-housing-oversupply-2026/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/ndis-sda-housing-oversupply-2026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let me save you some money.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been targeted by a property spruiker, a &amp;ldquo;wealth coach,&amp;rdquo; or a slick marketing funnel promising 10%+ rental yields from NDIS SDA (Specialist Disability Accommodation) housing, you need to read this before you sign anything.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not saying SDA housing is a scam. It&amp;rsquo;s not. There are legitimate SDA providers doing important work housing Australians with significant disabilities. The NDIS SDA program exists for a critical reason, and the people living in these homes genuinely need them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
