<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bush Digital Guides</title>
    <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bush Digital Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Granny Flat Investment Australia 2026: The State-by-State Guide to Boosting Your Rental Yield</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/granny-flat-investment-australia-2026-state-by-state-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/granny-flat-investment-australia-2026-state-by-state-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been sitting on a decent-sized block wondering how to squeeze more income out of it, you&amp;rsquo;re not alone. Granny flat investment in Australia has absolutely exploded over the past few years — and in 2026, the numbers are making more sense than ever.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With national home values up 8.8% over 2025 according to PropTrack, rental vacancy rates still tight in most capitals, and building costs starting to stabilise after the post-COVID blowout, adding a secondary dwelling to your existing property is one of the smartest value-add plays going around.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zoning Reform Could Slash $100K Off House Prices — What It Means for Property Investors</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/zoning-reform-property-investment-australia-2026/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/zoning-reform-property-investment-australia-2026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What if the biggest opportunity — and the biggest threat — to your property portfolio isn&amp;rsquo;t interest rates, CGT changes, or immigration numbers?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What if it&amp;rsquo;s the way councils draw lines on maps?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Grattan Institute has just dropped a major report arguing that Australia could knock &lt;strong&gt;more than $100,000 off the typical house price&lt;/strong&gt; simply by changing how we zone our suburbs. No new taxes. No government handouts. Just letting people build the homes that are actually needed, where they&amp;rsquo;re actually needed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CGT Discount Changes: What Australian Property Investors Need to Know in 2026</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/cgt-discount-changes-what-property-investors-need-to-know-2026/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 08:30:00 +1030</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/cgt-discount-changes-what-property-investors-need-to-know-2026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been anywhere near the news this past fortnight, you&amp;rsquo;ll have noticed something big brewing: the federal government is openly floating changes to the capital gains tax discount. For the first time in years, senior Labor figures aren&amp;rsquo;t shutting down the conversation — they&amp;rsquo;re leaning into it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For property investors, particularly those of us running value-add strategies, this could be a genuine game-changer. So let&amp;rsquo;s cut through the political noise and figure out what&amp;rsquo;s actually happening, what it means for your portfolio, and whether you should be panicking or planning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Job Management Software for Tradies in Australia (2026 Honest Review)</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/best-job-management-software-tradies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/best-job-management-software-tradies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every tradie hits the same wall. You&amp;rsquo;re good at your trade, business is growing, but admin is eating you alive. Quotes going out late, jobs double-booked, invoices in a pile. You&amp;rsquo;re running your business from text messages, a notebook, and whatever you remember after your third coffee.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Job management software fixes this. But choosing the wrong one is almost worse than having none — you&amp;rsquo;ll spend weeks setting it up, hate using it, and go back to the notebook within a month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Smart Irrigation Controllers in Australia (2026 Compared)</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/smart-irrigation-controllers-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/smart-irrigation-controllers-australia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a particular frustration that comes with staring at brown patches in summer, knowing you forgot to run the sprinklers. Or worse — copping a water bill because the timer ran through a week of rain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Smart irrigation controllers fix both problems. They connect to weather data, adjust automatically, and let you control everything from your phone. But which one actually works in Australia?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not American units that technically ship here but have no local weather support — the ones that work with our climate data, our water restrictions, and our conditions. Here are the four worth your money in 2026.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Duplex Build Costs in Australia 2026: What It Really Costs (No BS)</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/duplex-build-costs-australia-2026/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/duplex-build-costs-australia-2026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been researching duplex builds in Australia, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably found a heap of articles quoting build costs that look suspiciously low. &amp;ldquo;Build a duplex for $400,000!&amp;rdquo; they say, conveniently forgetting to mention the $185,000-$416,000 in additional costs that turn your &amp;ldquo;affordable development&amp;rdquo; into something that makes your accountant sweat.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s fix that. This guide gives you the &lt;strong&gt;real duplex build costs in Australia for 2026&lt;/strong&gt; — construction costs per square metre, the hidden costs nobody talks about upfront, actual case studies from recent builds, and the financing realities you need to plan for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home Assistant Garden Automation: A Practical Getting-Started Guide</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/home-assistant-garden-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/home-assistant-garden-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a certain kind of person who looks at their garden irrigation timer and thinks, &amp;ldquo;Yeah, but what if my garden could check the weather forecast, read the soil moisture, and decide for itself whether to water?&amp;rdquo; If that sounds like you, welcome to the rabbit hole. &lt;strong&gt;Home Assistant garden automation&lt;/strong&gt; is where smart home tech meets practical horticulture, and once you start, you won&amp;rsquo;t look at a dumb timer the same way again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Automate Invoice Chasing for Your Small Business in Australia</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/automate-invoice-chasing-small-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/automate-invoice-chasing-small-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s be real for a second. You didn&amp;rsquo;t start a business to spend your evenings sending awkward &amp;ldquo;just following up on that invoice&amp;rdquo; emails. Nobody did. Yet here we are — the Australian Small Business and Family Enterprise Ombudsman reports that late payments cost Australian small businesses over &lt;strong&gt;$115 billion&lt;/strong&gt; in outstanding invoices at any given time. The average payment time for small business invoices in Australia sits around &lt;strong&gt;30-35 days&lt;/strong&gt; beyond the due date.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a Wicking Bed in Australia: The Complete Guide</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/wicking-bed-guide-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/wicking-bed-guide-australia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever watched your raised garden beds turn into a dusty wasteland during an Aussie summer, wicking beds might just change your life. They&amp;rsquo;re not new — people have been building them for years — but they&amp;rsquo;re having a proper moment right now, and for good reason. When water restrictions tighten up and your council starts sending passive-aggressive letters about hose usage, a garden that waters itself from the bottom up starts looking pretty bloody clever.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NDIS SDA Housing Investment in 2026: The Oversupply Nobody Warned You About</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/ndis-sda-housing-oversupply-2026/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/ndis-sda-housing-oversupply-2026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let me save you some money.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been targeted by a property spruiker, a &amp;ldquo;wealth coach,&amp;rdquo; or a slick marketing funnel promising 10%+ rental yields from NDIS SDA (Specialist Disability Accommodation) housing, you need to read this before you sign anything.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not saying SDA housing is a scam. It&amp;rsquo;s not. There are legitimate SDA providers doing important work housing Australians with significant disabilities. The NDIS SDA program exists for a critical reason, and the people living in these homes genuinely need them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar Battery Rebate Australia 2026: STCs, the Cheaper Home Batteries Program &amp; What Changes in May</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/solar-battery-stc-rebate-2026/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/solar-battery-stc-rebate-2026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been quoted for a home battery system recently, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably seen a line item for &amp;ldquo;STC rebate&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;government incentive&amp;rdquo; that knocks a few thousand dollars off the price. Nice bonus, right?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the thing most people don&amp;rsquo;t realise: that rebate is about to change significantly. From &lt;strong&gt;May 2026&lt;/strong&gt;, the way Small-scale Technology Certificates (STCs) apply to batteries is getting restructured. Depending on the size of the battery you&amp;rsquo;re looking at, you could be looking at a noticeably smaller discount if you wait.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starlink vs NBN for Rural Australia in 2026: The Honest Comparison</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/starlink-vs-nbn-rural-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/starlink-vs-nbn-rural-australia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you live outside a major Australian city, you know the internet situation has been&amp;hellip; let&amp;rsquo;s call it &amp;ldquo;character building.&amp;rdquo; Between NBN Sky Muster&amp;rsquo;s data caps, Fixed Wireless congestion, and the old ADSL connections that some rural areas are still limping along on, getting reliable internet in regional Australia has been one of the great ongoing frustrations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then Starlink showed up, and suddenly rural Australians had an alternative that actually worked. But it&amp;rsquo;s 2026 now, Starlink has matured, NBN has made upgrades, and the question of &lt;strong&gt;Starlink vs NBN for rural Australia&lt;/strong&gt; deserves a fresh, honest look.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Bush Digital Guides</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-short-version&#34;&gt;The Short Version&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We write practical guides for Australians. No filler. No corporate speak. Just stuff that actually helps.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-slightly-longer-version&#34;&gt;The Slightly Longer Version&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bush Digital Guides started because we were tired of reading books that promised everything and delivered nothing. You know the type — 200 pages that could&amp;rsquo;ve been a blog post, padded with motivational quotes and &amp;ldquo;mindset&amp;rdquo; chapters that say the same thing five different ways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We decided to write the books we wished existed. Books packed with real data, real product comparisons, real Australian prices, and real stories from people who&amp;rsquo;ve actually done the thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automate Everything</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/books/automate-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/books/automate-everything/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-inside&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Inside&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You didn&amp;rsquo;t start a business to become a professional email-replier. But here you are — chasing invoices at 10pm, losing customers because you forgot to send the quote, and wondering where your weekend went.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book fixes that. Not with vague AI hype or enterprise software you can&amp;rsquo;t afford, but with practical tools that Australian small businesses can set up on a Saturday arvo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;who-its-for&#34;&gt;Who It&amp;rsquo;s For&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tradies running solo or with a small crew&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Consultants stuck in feast-or-famine cycles&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Small business owners spending more time on admin than actual work&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Anyone who&amp;rsquo;s ever sent 47 duplicate invoices by accident (that&amp;rsquo;s a real story, and it&amp;rsquo;s in the book)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-youll-learn&#34;&gt;What You&amp;rsquo;ll Learn&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part 1 — The Mindset:&lt;/strong&gt; Where your time actually goes (not where you think it goes), the automation stack explained in plain English, and how to audit your time leaks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off-Grid but Online</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/books/off-grid-but-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/books/off-grid-but-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-inside&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Inside&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to choose between modern comfort and self-sufficiency. This book shows you how to build a home that generates its own power, catches its own water, grows its own food — and still has decent WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Written from real Australian conditions (not American fantasies about Montana cabins), this covers everything from solar system sizing to Starlink installation, from rainwater filtration to composting toilets that don&amp;rsquo;t make your guests cry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Set and Forget</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/books/set-and-forget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/books/set-and-forget/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-inside&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Inside&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Australia is one of the driest inhabited continents on Earth. Adelaide gets less rain than London. And yet we keep watering our gardens with the sophistication of a bloke with a thumb over a hose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book changes that. From smart irrigation controllers that check the weather forecast and skip watering when rain&amp;rsquo;s coming, to soil moisture sensors that tell you exactly when your tomatoes are thirsty, to complete Home Assistant setups that run your entire garden automatically.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Value-Add Property Playbook</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/books/value-add-property-playbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/books/value-add-property-playbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-inside&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Inside&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The traditional property playbook — buy a house, hope it goes up, buy another one in seven years — is painfully slow. This book is for investors who want to actively create equity, not just wait for it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every strategy. Every state&amp;rsquo;s rules. Real numbers, not &amp;ldquo;indicative estimates.&amp;rdquo; From granny flats to NDIS housing, with honest assessments of what works and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;who-its-for&#34;&gt;Who It&amp;rsquo;s For&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Property investors who already own 1-2 properties and want to accelerate&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Anyone considering a granny flat, duplex, or subdivision&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Investors who want real data instead of seminar hype&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;People who&amp;rsquo;ve been burned by spruikers and want the unvarnished truth&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-youll-learn&#34;&gt;What You&amp;rsquo;ll Learn&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part 1 — Foundations:&lt;/strong&gt; The mindset shift, understanding zoning (the 30 minutes that saves $100,000), feasibility studies with real templates, and assembling your team of 15 professionals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
