<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Bush Digital Guides</title>
    <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Bush Digital Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <atom:link href="https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automate Everything</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/books/automate-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/books/automate-everything/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-inside&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Inside&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You didn&amp;rsquo;t start a business to become a professional email-replier. But here you are — chasing invoices at 10pm, losing customers because you forgot to send the quote, and wondering where your weekend went.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book fixes that. Not with vague AI hype or enterprise software you can&amp;rsquo;t afford, but with practical tools that Australian small businesses can set up on a Saturday arvo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;who-its-for&#34;&gt;Who It&amp;rsquo;s For&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tradies running solo or with a small crew&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Consultants stuck in feast-or-famine cycles&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Small business owners spending more time on admin than actual work&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Anyone who&amp;rsquo;s ever sent 47 duplicate invoices by accident (that&amp;rsquo;s a real story, and it&amp;rsquo;s in the book)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-youll-learn&#34;&gt;What You&amp;rsquo;ll Learn&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part 1 — The Mindset:&lt;/strong&gt; Where your time actually goes (not where you think it goes), the automation stack explained in plain English, and how to audit your time leaks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off-Grid but Online</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/books/off-grid-but-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/books/off-grid-but-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-inside&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Inside&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to choose between modern comfort and self-sufficiency. This book shows you how to build a home that generates its own power, catches its own water, grows its own food — and still has decent WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Written from real Australian conditions (not American fantasies about Montana cabins), this covers everything from solar system sizing to Starlink installation, from rainwater filtration to composting toilets that don&amp;rsquo;t make your guests cry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Set and Forget</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/books/set-and-forget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/books/set-and-forget/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-inside&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Inside&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Australia is one of the driest inhabited continents on Earth. Adelaide gets less rain than London. And yet we keep watering our gardens with the sophistication of a bloke with a thumb over a hose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book changes that. From smart irrigation controllers that check the weather forecast and skip watering when rain&amp;rsquo;s coming, to soil moisture sensors that tell you exactly when your tomatoes are thirsty, to complete Home Assistant setups that run your entire garden automatically.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Value-Add Property Playbook</title>
      <link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/books/value-add-property-playbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/books/value-add-property-playbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-inside&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Inside&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The traditional property playbook — buy a house, hope it goes up, buy another one in seven years — is painfully slow. This book is for investors who want to actively create equity, not just wait for it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every strategy. Every state&amp;rsquo;s rules. Real numbers, not &amp;ldquo;indicative estimates.&amp;rdquo; From granny flats to NDIS housing, with honest assessments of what works and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;who-its-for&#34;&gt;Who It&amp;rsquo;s For&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Property investors who already own 1-2 properties and want to accelerate&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Anyone considering a granny flat, duplex, or subdivision&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Investors who want real data instead of seminar hype&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;People who&amp;rsquo;ve been burned by spruikers and want the unvarnished truth&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-youll-learn&#34;&gt;What You&amp;rsquo;ll Learn&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part 1 — Foundations:&lt;/strong&gt; The mindset shift, understanding zoning (the 30 minutes that saves $100,000), feasibility studies with real templates, and assembling your team of 15 professionals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
