<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Value-Add Property on Bush Digital Guides</title><link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/tags/value-add-property/</link><description>Recent content in Value-Add Property on Bush Digital Guides</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-au</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 08:30:00 +1030</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/tags/value-add-property/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CGT Discount Changes: What Australian Property Investors Need to Know in 2026</title><link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/cgt-discount-changes-what-property-investors-need-to-know-2026/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 08:30:00 +1030</pubDate><guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/cgt-discount-changes-what-property-investors-need-to-know-2026/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;ve been anywhere near the news this past fortnight, you&amp;rsquo;ll have noticed something big brewing: the federal government is openly floating changes to the capital gains tax discount. For the first time in years, senior Labor figures aren&amp;rsquo;t shutting down the conversation — they&amp;rsquo;re leaning into it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For property investors, particularly those of us running value-add strategies, this could be a genuine game-changer. So let&amp;rsquo;s cut through the political noise and figure out what&amp;rsquo;s actually happening, what it means for your portfolio, and whether you should be panicking or planning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Duplex Build Costs in Australia 2026: What It Really Costs (No BS)</title><link>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/duplex-build-costs-australia-2026/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bushdigitalguides.com.au/blog/duplex-build-costs-australia-2026/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;ve been researching duplex builds in Australia, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably found a heap of articles quoting build costs that look suspiciously low. &amp;ldquo;Build a duplex for $400,000!&amp;rdquo; they say, conveniently forgetting to mention the $185,000-$416,000 in additional costs that turn your &amp;ldquo;affordable development&amp;rdquo; into something that makes your accountant sweat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s fix that. This guide gives you the &lt;strong>real duplex build costs in Australia for 2026&lt;/strong> — construction costs per square metre, the hidden costs nobody talks about upfront, actual case studies from recent builds, and the financing realities you need to plan for.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>